

Stephanie Hotz Senior art director | UX/UI designer

PROFILE

I'm Stephanie, a senior art director, UX/UI designer and interdisciplinary concepter based in Berlin, Germany.

I believe in a natural and inventive culture where the work of multi-disciplinary thinkers can come together and find its way into society.

I always focus on the user's experience in the specific context of each project – whether for an artwork, branding and/or a digital service. I'm here to generate great user experiences that solve everyday problems.

SERVICES

BRANDING > Creative and art direction, Concept and visual design

> Brand and corporate design, Packaging, Finishing, Production and supervision

UX/UI > User journeys und user flows, User personas

DESIGN > Information architecture, Usability testing and analysis

> Wireframing and rapid prototyping, UI components and documentation

> Asset creation and developer handouts

> Developer friendly basics in HTML, CSS and JavaScript

TOOLSET > Adobe CS, Sketch, Balsamiq, InVision, Figma, Zeplin, Slack, and many more

EXPERIENCE

07.2018 - PRESENT

Senior art director and UX/UI designer working for corporates, institutions and agencies 11.2014 - 06.2018

Senior art director working for corporates, institutions and agencies on concept, branding, packaging, campaigning, finishing, supervision and project management

02.2008 - 10.2014

Visual designer and art director

01.2007 - 02.2008

Junior art director @Jung von Matt/Alster Werbeagentur GmbH, Hamburg, Germany

SEIT 2006 - PRESENT

Art projects, exhibitions, grants and granted residencies

EDUCATION

04.2019 - Certified: Frontend development @CareerFoundry

07.2018 - Certified: UX designer @CareerFoundry

02.2008 - 10.2009 Graduate studies "Fine arts", Bauhaus-University Weimar, Germany

04.2005 - 04.2006 Exchange studies "Intermedia arts", Tōkyō Geijutsu Daigaku, Tokyo, Japan

09.2003 - 04.2004 Exchange studies "Diseño gráfico", EINA - Centre Universitari de Disseny i Art, Barcelona, Spain

10.1999 - 09.2006 Diploma studies "Fine arts", Bauhaus-University Weimar, Germany

LANGUAGES

German = native, Englisch = fluent, French, spanish and japanese = basic